Instead of using an all around averaging filter,
除了全均值过滤器
we may want to filter that both blurs and image and better preserves the edges in it.
有时我们会想要个既能模糊图像 又能更好地保存图像边缘的过滤器
And for that we use gaussian blur.
为此 我们可用高斯模糊
This is perhaps the most frequently used low-pass filter in computer vision applications.
这或许是计算机视觉应用中最常用的低通过滤器了
It's essentially a weighted average that gives the most weight to the center pixel,
低通过滤器其实就是加权平均法 赋予中心像素最大的权重
but also takes into account
但也会考虑到
the surrounding pixels more so depending on how close they are to the center.
周围的像素 权重多少主要取决于周围像素有多接近中心像素
This is similar to the first edge detection filter we went through,
这与我们讲过的第一个边缘检测过滤器类似
only these components are all positive,
但这个过滤器的所有元素都是正值
normalized, and summed to one.
而且经过归一化处理 总和为 1
Here, I read in the same image of a brain that you've seen before with speckle noise.
这里我读取了一张大脑图 就是之前讲斑点噪声的那张
And we can see that noise better,
如果稍微放大一下
if we zoom in a little bit.
我们就能更清楚地看到这些噪声
And I'm going to go through applying a Gaussian blur filter to reduce this noise.
我要用高斯模糊过滤器来降噪
Before I filter the image,
在进行滤波处理之前
I first have to convert it to grayscale.
首先要将图像转换为灰度图
Then, because this filter is so commonly used,
由于这个过滤器很常用
openCV provides a function to use it called Gaussian blur.
所以 OpenCV 提供了一个叫 GaussianBlur 的函数
This function takes in our grayscale image,
这个高斯模糊函数要输入的参数有灰度图像、
the size we want our kernel to be,
核大小
which I'll put as five by five,
这里我将核大小设为五乘五
which is slightly bigger than our usual three by three.
比之前常说的三乘三稍微大些
And lastly, our standard deviation which will
最后是标准差
automatically be calculated if I set this to zero,
如果把标准差设为 0 函数就会自动计算
and you can learn more about this math in text.
具体数学运算请见文本
For now, know that creating a bigger filter will create a slightly bigger blur.
要知道 过滤器建得越大 模糊范围就会越大
We still need the filter it to be of odd dimensions
过滤器的维数还得是奇数
that we can center each pixel of our image in this kernel.
这样才能把图像的每个像素作为核的中心
Then I'll plot these images side by side.
我把这些图像并排列出来
Here's our original grayscale image,
这是原始的灰度图像
and next to it is this blurred version.
旁边的这个是模糊处理过的版本
If we zoom in, we can see that the speckle in
要是把图像放大 我们就能看见
this original image is significantly reduced in this blurred image.
在模糊图像中 原图有的斑点明显减少了许多
Lastly, I'll apply a sobel edge detector to
最后 用 sobel 边缘检测器
both the unblurred grayscale image and the blurred version to compare their performance.
对未模糊处理的灰度图像和经过模糊处理的图像分别进行操作 比较两者的效果
Using filter2D, I'm creating both high pass filtered images: One,
用 filter2D 对两个图像分别进行高通滤波处理 一个图像是
using our original grayscale and one using our blurred version.
原始的灰度图像 另一个是模糊处理后的图像
And again I'll plot both side by side.
还是将两张图像并排绘制出来
You can see that the non-blurred image is
你可以看到未模糊处理的图像
much noisier and the blurred image has more accurate edge detection,
噪声更多 而模糊处理后的图像边缘检测效果更准确
especially in the brain tissue region that we care most about.
特别是我们最关心的脑组织区域
For this and many other images,
通常来讲 对于这个图像以及其它诸多图像
it's very common to first pass an image through
我们都会先对图像进行小型低通滤波处理
a small low pass filter like a Gaussian blur to get rid of noise,
比如应用高斯模糊 从而去除噪声
and then apply a high pass filter for edge detection.
然后再用高通过滤器来检测边缘
So keep this ordering in mind as you filter images.
所以在对图像进行滤波处理时 请牢牢记住这个顺序